# DANIEL BAILEY

## **GAMES DEVELOPMENT GRADUATE**

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelors A-Levels

Staffordshire University North Lindsey College

Games Development 2:1 Physics B, Maths B, Psychology C

2016 - 2020 2014 - 2016

#### **DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE**

## C# & C++

- Games
- Game Engines
- 00P
- SOLID
- TCP/UDP Networking

## Game Engines

- Unity 2D/3D
- Unreal Engine 4
- Console/PC
- Mobile

# Web Development

- HTML
- CSS/SCSS
- JavaScript/Typescript/JQuery
- REST
- SQL
- .NET
- MVC
- Razor

# **Development Process**

- Version Control (Git/GitHub)
- Azure/Devops
- Agile Methodologies (SCRUM, Kanban)
- Trello
- Microsoft Teams

#### **PROFILE**

I am a graduate of Staffordshire University with a 2:1 in Games Development. I am working as a Graduate Software Engineer at BEP Systems. I have experience using game engines, fullstack web development and programming in the languages C#, C++, HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

#### CONTACT

#### Address

38 Ryall Avenue Salford Greater Manchester M5 3HX

#### Phone Number

07542886642

## **Email**

danbailey.813@gmail.com

## Website

danrbailey.netlify.com

# Social Media

Twitter: DanielRBailey LinkedIn: danrbailey

References available on request

## **PROJECTS**

## Mobile Game

- Unity
- C#
- Arcade Mobile Game
- Released to Android
- Monetized using ads and in-app purchases

# Mobile Rhythm Game

- Unity
- C#
- Rhythm-Based
- Synth-wave theme
- Focus on player-retention

# Puzzle Game for the Motor Impaired

- Unreal Engine 4/Unity
- C#
- C++
- Blueprints
- Single Input

# Couch Co-op Party Game

- Unreal Engine 4
- C++
- Blueprints
- Local Multiplayer
- Controller Support

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# February 2021 - Present

Graduate Developer

**BEP Systems** 

Manchester

July 2019 - June 2020

Team Member

Roadchef

Roadchef Stafford

January 2014 - July 2016

**Chef Assistant** 

D'Litas Cakes and Catering

Scunthorpe